Charles Wesley Snow Collection
Charles Wesley Snow Collection
1861-1928
0.25 linear ft.
Charles Wesley Snow was a Syracuse-area entrepreneur and active member of the community. Correspondence to and from members of hisfamily, also including some clippings and a few "seance letters."
4854638
Biographical History
Charles Wesley Snow (1835-1918) was an entrepreneur and businessman in Syracuse, New York. For many years he owned and operated a thriving patent medicine business, both retail and wholesale, under the name C.W. Snow & Co. He was also highly active in the community: among other things, he was one of the incorporators of the Syracuse Chamber of Commerce, director of the First National Bank of Syracuse, a member of the board of trustees for May Memorial Church, the Onondaga Historical Association, and St. Joseph's Hospital, a Mason of both the York and Scottish Rite, and a Knight Templar.
Snow married Harriet L. Powers, daughter of Harriet and Nelson Clement Power, in 1863. Their son Nelson Powers Snow married Fannie Bates, with whom he had a daughter Frances (1898). Their daughter Carolyn L. Snow (Carrie) married Irving S. Merrell; the couple had a son Seward S. (1899), daughter Mary (1901), daughter Harriet (1906).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Charles Wesley Snow Collection consists largely of correspondence, with a few other miscellaneous items.
Correspondence is to and from members of the Charles Wesley Snow family. Represented in the collection are Charles himself and his wife Harriet (Hattie), their daughter Carolyn (Carrie), and Carolyn's daughter Harriet and daughter-in-law Fannie Bates Snow and her mother. Harriet Snow's father N. C. Power and various cousins are also represented. Scattered through the collection are various clippings, most notably several pertaining to Carolyn's brother-in-law Lewis S. Merrell; the Merrell family was quite wealthy and the divorce received attention from the press.
The collection also includes some Miscellany: a few small sheets of paper with notes about social events, some genealogical material, and a folder of so-called "seance letters." Such letters, also known as spirit writing or automatic writing, were produced by mediums allegedly by way of contact with spirits or with deceased family members. They were very popular in the late 19th century.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical.
Subject and Genre Headings
New York State; Snow, Charles Wesley.; C.W. Snow & Co.; Businessmen -- New York (State) -- Syracuse.; Freemasons -- New York (State); Spirit writings.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- History.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Automatic writing.; Correspondence.; Clippings (information artifacts)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unknown.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Bates, Fannie E. (Fannie Bates Snow's mother), 1891-1893; 1918; includes obituary (Box 1)
  - Snow, Fannie Bates (daughter-in-law), 1891 (Box 1)
  - Brower [?], Lillian B., 1928 (Box 1)
  - Lang, Mary, 1905; undated; includes clipping about visit to Syracuse by her and her husband, Sir John Lang (Box 1)
  - Mills, Royal (nephew), 1883 (Box 1)
  - Merrell, Carolyn Snow (daughter; wife of irving S. Merrell), 1896; 1898,; 1913-1914,; 1917,; undated (Box 1)
  - Merrell, Lewis C. (Irving S. Merrell's brother), 1914; clippings about his divorce (Box 1)
  - Minford, Reba (Mrs. Richard L.), 1926; includes clipping about Florida hurricane (Box 1)
  - Powers, Mrs. N. C. (mother-in-law), 1898 (Box 1)
  - Snow, Charles Wesley, 1893; 1900-1901,; 1906,; 1909-1912,; 1917-1920; includes clippings (Box 1)
  - Tibbitts, Eloise, 1928 (Box 1)
  - Wright, Caroline A. (cousin?), 1862-1865 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, 1861-1863; undated (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  - Clippings, Wieting Opera House, 1881; undated (Box 1)
  - Genealogical material, Bates, Merrell, Powers, Smith, Snow families (Box 1)
  - Journal pages, 1909-1910; 1913,; 1916-1917,; 1920,; undated; several headed "Social Events" (Box 1)
  - Seance letters, 1908; 1920,; undated (Box 1)